Black Sparrow Press Collection, 1966-1994 (bulk 1973-1993)
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Black Sparrow Press Collection, 1966-1994 (bulk 1973-1993)
MS 538
Black Sparrow Press
Black Sparrow Press was a small independent publishing house focused on avant-garde literature. Produced by John and Barbara Martin, with the help of typographer and printer Graham Mackintosh, the Press was responsible for drawing attention to Charles Bukowski and his literary work. Each published title includes correspondence from authors, layout matter and artwork, ephemera, photographs, manuscripts, proofs, and first editions. Black Sparrow Press published a number of American and English authors including Diane Wakoski, Joyce Carol Oates, Robert Creeley, Charles Olson, John Fante, Gerard Malanga, Wanda Coleman, and acquired publication rights for Wyndham Lewis and D. H. Lawrence.
133 linear ft.
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL: http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
There are no restrictions on this collection.
Historical Note
John Martin founded Black Sparrow Press in 1966, using proceeds from the sale of his personal book collection and with the goal of publishing the work of Charles Bukowski, whom Martin believed in and considered “the new Walt Whitman.” The Press, based out of California, started out as a side job for then office supply manager Martin. By 1972, Martin purchased a print shop in Santa Barbara and devoted himself full-time to the endeavor; in 1986, the Press moved north to Santa Rosa. The rest of the Black Sparrow Press staff included Barbara Martin, who designed over 700 of the book jackets, and typographer Graham Mackintosh, who remained in charge of printing for most of the 36 years that the independent publisher was in business.
Following the publication of its first broadsides by Bukowski, Black Sparrow Press focused on the publication of contemporary, avant-garde literature. Starting with Black Mountain Poets Robert Creeley, Edward Dorn, and Larry Eigner, it followed with young authors from the New York City area, including Diane Wakoski and Clayton Eshleman. There were also West Coast poets Michael McClure, David Bromige, and David Meltzer, and others like Gerard Malanga, James Tate, and Wanda Coleman. Among the prose authors published are Fielding Dawson, James Purdy, and Paul Goodman.
Martin’s business strategy was to issue expensive limited-edition letterpress hardbacks that would produce a profit, followed by economical and more popular paperbacks that faithful readers could purchase. Black Sparrow Press published on average 10 to12 books a year: first limited editions sported title pages in color and all printings afterwards were done in black and white. Refusing to fund himself through grants, Martin relied on sales to stay afloat and sold carefully maintained archives to university special collections when in need of funds. In the beginning, Black Sparrow Press sold its books to independent bookstores, and editions in those years reached around 3,000; over time, however, 80% of printings went to Barnes and #38; Noble, Borders, and Ingram, leading to editions of 15,000 per book. In 2002, Martin retired from publishing, selling the rights of 49 titles to HarperCollins’ imprint, Ecco Press. The remaining inventory went to Boston-based publisher, David R. Godine, who continues to sell reprints of the works under the name Black Sparrow Books.
Arrangement
This collection is organized into four series
Series I: Book Files, 1973-1993
Series II: General Correspondence, 1971-1982
Series III: Publicity Materials and Publication Lists, 1966-1994
Series IV: Arabesque Books, 1981
Scope and Content Note
The collection is arranged in chronological order, following the order of publication in Bradford Morrow and Seamus Cooney’s 1981 work, A Bibliography of the Black Sparrow Press, 1966-1978. John Martin sold his archive to several university libraries: the University of Alberta (Edmonton) has works one to fifty, Pennsylvania State University (Pittsburg) holds works fifty one to one hundred fifty, the University of New Mexico (Albuquerque) acquired works one fifty one to one sixty two, one sixty four to one ninety eight, two hundred to two hundred seven, two hundred nine to two hundred twelve, two hundred twenty seven, two hundred thirty eight, and two hundred fifty. The University of Arizona owns works missing from New Mexico’s one hundred sixty three to two hundred forty nine sequence, as well as works two hundred fifty to five hundred nine. Martin sold the reminder files to the University of California Berkeley, who holds works published during 1992 to 2002, Black Sparrow Press’ last decade.
Files for each work in the collection include correspondence from authors and others involved in their production (very few instances of responses from John Martin or anyone else at Black Sparrow Press are included), layout materials and artwork, original manuscripts, revisions and proofs, and all hardcovers and softcover issues for each title.
Aside from correspondence directly related with each of the works, the collection includes general correspondence received by John Martin (again, with very few responses by the publisher) that deal with simple business transactions and that sometimes have attached manuscripts from authors hoping to catch Martin’s attention.
The Press produced two works, Paul Outerbridge’s Singular Aesthetic and Harvey Mudd’s The Plain of Smokes, as part of the Arabesque Books imprint, the trade name used by Black Sparrow Press to publish art books and catalogue resumes. Oversized materials include Robert Crumb’s Comics, Bukowski’s artwork for Septuagenarian Stew and Hollywood, original serigraph prints by Ken Price from Harvey Mudd’s The Plain of Smokes, and others.
Bowles, Paul, 1910-1999.; Bukowski, Charles.; Coleman, Wanda.; Cooney, Seamus.; Creeley, Robert, 1926-2005.; Dawson, Fielding, 1930-2002.; Eigner, Larry, 1927-1996.; Eshleman, Clayton.; Fante, John, 1909-1983.; Goodman, Paul, 1911-1972.; Jaffe, Sherril, 1945-.; Kelly, Robert, 1935-.; Lawrence, D. H. (David Herbert), 1885-1930.; Lewis, Wyndham, 1882-1957.; Malanga, Gerard.; Martin, John.; Olson, Charles, 1910-1970.; Oates, Joyce Carol, 1938.; Reznikoff, Charles, 1894-1976.; Sanford, John B., 1904-[2003].; Wakoski, Diane.; Yau, John, 1950-.; Ampersand Books.; Aquila Publishing Company.; Arabesque (Firm).; Black Sparrow Press.; California Rehabilitation Center.; Committee of Small Magazine Editors and Publishers (U.S.).; Crepuscular Press.; Gay Sunshine Press.; Litmus Inc.; Menard Press; Mudborn Press.; New Directions Publishing Corp.; Pentagram Press.; Pushcart Press.; Unicorn Press.; University of California, Los Angeles. Library.; University of California, San Diego. Library.; University of California, Santa Barbara. Library.; American Poetry – 20th Century.; American Literature – 20th Century.; Authors and Publishers – 20th Century.; Publishers and Publishing – United States – California.; Small Presses – United States.; Santa Rosa (Calif.).
Container List
- Series I: Book Files, 1973-1993
  This series is arranged in chronological order and each project is organized according to the process of production, which is partially documented in A Bibliography of the Black Sparrow Press, 1966-1978 (Cooney, Morrow, 1981). Most book files include correspondence from authors and others involved in their production (very few instances of responses from John Martin or anyone else at Black Sparrow Press are included), layout materials and artwork; original manuscripts; revisions and proofs; 1 to 2 limited edition hardcovers, and 2 to 4 paperbacks for each work. Also in this series are limited edition Black Sparrow Press New Year’s Greetings created by Charles Bukowski.
  - #163 Dancing on the Grave of a Son of a Bitch, Wakoski, Diane, Correspondence, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - #163 Dancing on the Grave of a Son of a Bitch, Wakoski, Diane, Manuscript, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - #163 Dancing on the Grave of a Son of a Bitch, Wakoski, Diane, Folded Signatures, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - #163 Dancing on the Grave of a Son of a Bitch, Wakoski, Diane, 2 Hardcover copies, 2 Softcovers, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - #199 Abalone, Wakoski, Diane, Manuscript, Proof, Artwork, Correspondence, 3 Hardcover copies, 1 Softcover, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - #208 Creating a Personal Mythology, Wakoski, Diane, First Manuscript, Second Manuscript, Proof, Booklet, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - #213 To Have Done with the Judgment of God, Artaud, Antonin, Correspondence, Manuscript, First Proof, Revision, Second Proof, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - #214 Explosion of the Swan and Three Poems, Malanga, Gerard, Manuscript, Proofs, Artwork, Lorca-Dali Photo, Correspondence, Notes, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - #215 The Gull Wall, Eshleman, Clayton, Correspondence, Artwork, Notes, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - #215 The Gull Wall, Eshleman, Clayton, Manuscript, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - #215 The Gull Wall, Eshleman, Clayton, 3 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - #216 Medusa and #38; Others, Stepanchev, Stephen, Correspondence, Manuscript, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - #217 The Cat’s Meow, Morris, Wright, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - #217 The Cat’s Meow, Morris, Wright, Manuscript Unbound Copy, 1 Hardcover, 2 Softcover, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - #218 The Loom, Kelly, Robert, Artwork, Correspondence, Miscellaneous, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - #218 The Loom, Kelly, Robert, Manuscript (1 of 3), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - #218 The Loom, Kelly, Robert, Manuscript (2 of 3), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - #218 The Loom, Kelly, Robert, Manuscript (3 of 3), 1975 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - #218 The Loom, Kelly, Robert, 2 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - #218 Ex Cranium, Rakosi, Carl, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - #218 Ex Cranium, Rakosi, Carl, Discarded Materials, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - #218 Ex Cranium, Rakosi, Carl, Manuscript, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - #218 Ex Cranium, Rakosi, Carl, 2 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - #220 Sparrow 25-36, 1 Hardcover, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - #221 Hadidan Aharam by Mohammed Mrabett, translated by Bowles, Paul, Manuscript, Correspondence, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - #222 Eight Fairy Tales, Loewinsohn, Ron, Manuscript, Copy, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - #223 The Journals, Blackburn, Paul, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - #223 The Journals, Blackburn, Paul, Manuscript, Manuscript (1 of 2), 1975 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - #223 The Journals, Blackburn, Paul, Manuscript (2 of 2), 1975 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - #223 The Journals, Blackburn, Paul, 2 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - #224 Squaw Valley, Jaffe, Sherril, Manuscript, Correspondence, Copy, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - #225 Factotum, Bukowski, Charles, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - #225 Factotum, Bukowski, Charles, Manuscript (1 of 2), 1975 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - #225 Factotum, Bukowski, Charles, Manuscript (2 of 2), 1975 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - #225 Factotum, Bukowski, Charles, Final Manuscript (1 of 2), 1975 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - #225 Factotum, Bukowski, Charles, Final Manuscript (2 of 2), 1975 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - #225 Factotum, Bukowski, Charles, 2 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - #226 The Last Poem and Tough Company, Wakoski, Diana and amp; Bukowski, Charles, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - #226 The Last Poem and Tough Company, Wakoski, Diana and amp; Bukowski, Charles, Manuscript, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - #226 The Last Poem and Tough Company, Wakoski, Diana and amp; Bukowski, Charles, 2 Hardcover, 2 Softcovers, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - #228 The Man Who Changed Overnight, Dawson, Fielding, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - #228 The Man Who Changed Overnight, Manuscript, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - #228 The Man Who Changed Overnight, Dawson, Fielding, 2 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - #229 Sixteen Odes, Kelly, Robert, Manuscript, Proofs, Correspondence, Copy, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - #230 Look and amp; Move On by Mohammed Mrabet, translated by Bowles, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - #230 Look and amp; Move On by Mohammed Mrabet, translated by Bowles, Paul, Manuscript, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - #230 Look and; Move On by Mohammed Mrabet, translated by Bowles, 3 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - #231 Credences of Winter, Bromige, David, Manuscript, Proofs, Correspondence, Copy, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - #232 Poems 1978-1936, Reznikoff, Charles, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - #232 Poems 1978-1936, Reznikoff, Charles, Manuscript, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - #232 Poems 1978-1936, Reznikoff, Charles, 3 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - #232 Look and amp; Move On by Mohammed Mrabet, translated by Bowles, By The Well of Living and amp; Seeing, notes for second printing, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - #233 Scarlet, Bukowski, Charles, Artwork, Manuscript, Proof, 2 Hardcover, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - #234 The Horses of the Sea, Olson, Charles, Manuscript, Proof, Correspondence, Copy, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - #235 Feminine Wiles, Bowles, Jane, Artwork, Correspondence, Photos, Notes, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - #235 Feminine Wiles, Bowles, Jane, Manuscript, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - #235 Feminine Wiles, Bowles, Jane, 1 Hardcover, 2 Softcovers, 1 File Copy, 1976 (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - #236 The Act of Poetry and Two Other Essays, Corman, Cid, Manuscript, Correspondence, Copy, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - #237 The Blessing, Oates, Joyce Carol, Manuscript, Proof, Correspondence, Copy, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - #238 D.H. Lawrence: Letters to Thomas and amp; Adele Seltzer, 1876-1940, Seltzer, Thomas, Correspondence [Gerald Lacy, Gerald Pollinger, John Martin], 1976 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - #239 A Dozen Oranges, Sorrentino, Gilbert, Manuscript, Correspondence, Copy, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - #240 The House of Leaves, Tarn, Nathaniel, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - #240 The House of Leaves, Tarn, Nathaniel, Manuscript, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - #240 The House of Leaves, Tarn, Nathaniel, 2 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1976 (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - #241 Poems for the Blue Sky, Koller, James, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - #241 Poems for the Blue Sky, Koller, James, Manuscript, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - #241 Poems for the Blue Sky, Koller, James, 2 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - #242 Artoud The Momo by Anthony Artaud, translated by Eshleman, Clayton and Glass, Norman, Manuscript, Correspondence, Copy, 1976 (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - #243 Harmless Poisons, Blameless Sins by Mohammed Mrabett, translated by Bowles, Paul, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - #243 Harmless Poisons, Blameless Sins by Mohammed Mrabett, translated by Bowles,Paul, Manuscript, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - #243 Harmless Poisons, Blameless Sins by Mohammed Mrabett, translated by Bowles,Paul, 3 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - #244 Devotion, Malanga, Gerard, Manuscript, Deleted Discarded Materials, Correspondence, Copy, 1976 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - #245 More Tiger Lilies, Dawson, Fielding, Manuscript, Correspondence, Copies (2), 1976 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - #246 Sparrow 37-48 1 Hardcover, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - #247 Six, Meltzer, David, Artwork, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - #247 Six, Meltzer, David, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - #247 Six, Meltzer, David, Manuscript, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - #247 Six, Meltzer, David, 2 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - #248 Variations on a Theme (An Essay on Revision), Wakoski, Diane, Correspondence, Manuscript, Proof, Copy, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - #249 Goat Dances, Loweinsohn, Ron, Artwork, Correspondence, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - #249 Goat Dances, Loweinsohn, Ron, Manuscript, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - #249 Goat Dances, Loweinsohn, Ron, 2 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1976 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - #251 Waiting for the King of Spain, Wakoski, Diane, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - #251 Waiting for the King of Spain, Wakoski, Diane, Manuscript, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - #251 Waiting for the King of Spain, Wakoski, Diane, 3 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - #252 For the Asking, Corman, Cid, Manuscript, Proof, Correspondence, Copy, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - #253 Art, Bukowski, Charles, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, Manuscript, Proofs, Miniature Books: 2 Hardcover, 2 Softcovers, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - #254 The Ring, Wakoski, Diane, Artwork, Correspondence, Manuscript, Proof, 2 Hardcover, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - #255 The Triumph of the Spider Monkey, Oates, Joyce Carol, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - #255 The Triumph of the Spider Monkey, Sunday Sentinel Magazine, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - #255 The Triumph of the Spider Monkey, Sunday Sentinel Magazine, Draft 1, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - #255 The Triumph of the Spider Monkey, Draft 2, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - #255 The Triumph of the Spider Monkey 3 Hardcovers, 2 soft-covers, 1 file copy, Northwest review, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - #256 First, There is the Need, Rezuikoff, Charles, manuscripts, proofs, copy, 1977 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - #257 My Experiences in Parnassus, Rakosi, Carl, manuscript, proofs, copy, 1977 (Box 18, File 7)
  - #258 Word for Word, Corman, Cid, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - #258 Word for Word,, Corman, Cid, Manuscript, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - #258 Word for Word, Corman, Cid, 3 Hardcover (1 signed), 1 Softcover, 1977 (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - #259 Maybe Tomorrow, Bukowski, Charles, Manuscript, Proofs, Copy, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - #260 Poems 1937-1975, Reznikoff, Charles, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - #260 Poems 1937-1975, Reznikoff, Charles, Draft (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - #260 Poems 1937-1975, Reznikoff, Charles, 3 Hardcover (1 signed), 1 Softcover, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - #261 On Us, Woolf, Douglas, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, 1977 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - #261 On Us, Woolf, Douglas, draft (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - #261 On Us, Woolf, Douglas, 2 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - #262 The Lady Of, Kelly, Robert, Manuscript, Correspondence, Copy, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - #263 Charles Reznikoff, Hindus, Milton, Artwork, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - #263 Charles Reznikoff, Hindus, Milton, Manuscript, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - #263 Charles Reznikoff, Hindus, Milton, 1 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - #264 The Big Mirror, by Mohammed Mrabet, translated by Bowles, Paul, Artwork, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - #264 The Big Mirror, by Mohammed Mrabet, translated by Bowles, Paul, Manuscript, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - #264 The Big Mirror, by Mohammed Mrabet, translated by Bowles, Paul, 3 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1977 (Box 21, Folder 8)
  - #265 Ascensions, Enslin, Theodore, Manuscript, Correspondence, Copy, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - #266 Daisy, Oates, Joyce Carol, Artwork, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 2)
  - #267 Daisy, Oates, Joyce Carol, 2 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 3)
  - #267 Core Meander, Eshleman, Clayton, Manuscript, Correspondence, Copy, 1977 (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - #268 Shadows of the Sun, Crosby, Harry, Artwork, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 1)
  - #268 Shadows of the Sun, Crosby, Harry, Photos, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - #268 Shadows of the Sun, Crosby, Harry, Correspondence, notes, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 3)
  - #268 Shadows of the Sun, Crosby, Harry, Proof, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - #268 Shadows of the Sun, Crosby, Harry, Draft 1, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - #268 Shadows of the Sun, Crosby, Harry, Draft 2, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 6)
  - #268 Shadows of the Sun, Crosby, Harry, Draft 3, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 7)
  - #268 Shadows of the Sun, Crosby, Harry, 2 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 8)
  - #269 Three Early Stories, Goodman, Paul, Manuscript, Artwork, Correspondence, Copy, 1977 (Box 23, Folder 9)
  - #270 White Sail, Sorrentino, Gilbert, Artwork, Correspondence, #270 White Sail, Sorrentino, Gilbert, Manuscript; #270 White Sail, Sorrentino, Gilbert, 2 Hardcover, 1 Softcover,; 1977 (Box 24, Folder 1, Folder 2, Folder 3)
  - #271 Things Gone and Things Still Here, Bowles, Paul, Artwork, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 1)
  - #271 Things Gone and Things Still Here, Bowles, Paul, Manuscript, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 2)
  - #271 Things Gone and Things Still Here, Bowles, Paul, 2 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1977 (Box 25, Folder 3)
  - #272 Ten Years After, Malanga, Gerard, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - #272 Ten Years After, Malanga, Gerard, Manuscript, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - #272 Ten Years After, Malanga, Gerard, Deleted Materials (Do Not Use), 1977 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - #272 Ten Years After, Malanga, Gerard, 2 Hardcover, 1 Softcover, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - #273 Art in the Court of the Blue Fag,Coleman, Wanda, Manuscript, Correspondence, Notes, 1977 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - #274 The World and its Streets,Places, Eigner, Larry, Artwork, Correspondence, Photos, Notes, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 1)
  - #274 The World and its Streets, Places, Eigner, Larry, Draft, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 2)
  - #274 The World and its Streets, Places, Eigner, Larry, 2 Hardcover, 1 Softcover (Box 27, Folder 3)
  - #275 Without Music, Palmer, Michael, Artwork, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 4)
  - #275 Without Music, Palmer, Michael, 4 file copies: 2 Hardcovers, 2 Softcovers, 1977 (Box 27, Folder 5)
  - #276 From Towards a New American Poetics, Faas, Ekbert, Manuscript, Correspondence, Copy, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - #277 Love is a Dog from Hell, Bukowski, Charles, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - #277 Love is a Dog from Hell, Bukowski, Charles, Draft, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - #277 Love is a Dog from Hell, Bukowski, Charles, Draft, Uncorrected Proof, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - #277 Love is a Dog from Hell, Bukowski, Charles, 1 Hardcover copies, 1 Softcover, 1977 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - #277 Love is a Dog from Hell, Bukowski, Charles, 2 hardcover copies, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - #278 The Manner “Music, Reznikoff, Charles, Artwork, Correspondence, Notes, Two Short Stories (From A Notebook, The Brazilian), 1977 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - #278 The Manner “Music, Reznikoff, Charles, edited proof, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - #278 The Manner “Music, Reznikoff, Charles, 2 Hardcover copies, 1 Softcover, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - #279 Summer Letters, Davidson, Michael, Manuscript, Proofs, Correspondence, Copy, 1977 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - #280 Sparrow 49-60, Hardcover copy, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - #281 Two Stories,, Shelnutt, Eve, Manuscript, Proofs, Correspondence, Copy, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - #282-283 Penny Lane and Two Penny Lane, Dawson, Fielding, Correspondence, artwork, notes for Penny Lane and Two Penny Lane, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - #282-283 Penny Lane and Two Penny Lane, Dawson, Fielding, Manuscript for Penny Lane, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - #282-283 Penny Lane and Two Penny Lane, Dawson, Fielding, Manuscript for Two Penny Lane, 1977 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - #282-283 Penny Lane and Two Penny Lane, Dawson, Fielding, 2 Hardcover copies, 1 Softcover for each, Penny Lane and Penny Lane (total of 6), 1977 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - #284 Season of Peril, Oates, Joyce Carol, Artwork, Manuscript, Correspondence, 1977 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - #284 Season of Peril,, Oates, Joyce Carol, Proof, Hardcover copies; 1977 (Box 31, Folder 2, Folder 3)